A Guide to the T. Turner Foster Papers, 1740-1978 (bulk 1920-1972)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
T. Turner Foster Papers, 1740-1978 (bulk 1920-1972)
The Library of Virginia
45111
20 cubic feet (47 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mr. and Mrs. John C. Palmer, Purcellville.
Biographical Information
Thomas Turner Foster was born on 1 August 1900. He was the son of James Robert Foster (1849-1919) and Mary deButts Carter (1871-1938). Turner Foster was a banker with the Fauquier National Bank of Warrenton, and also owned and operated a farm in The Plains, Virginia called "Glenville." Foster died in an automobile accident in Henrico County, Virginia on 28 November 1978.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1740-1978, of T. Turner Foster (1900-1978) of The Plains, Fauquier County, Virginia. Includes correspondence, financial records, subject files, records of his service on the Scott County Road Board, and materials relating to his establishment of a branch of the Millard Institute of Normal Speech in Warrenton. The bulk of the collection covers the years 1920 to 1972.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Correspondence.
II. Financial Records.
III. Subject Files.
IV. Scott District Road Board Records.
V. Millard Institute of Normal Speech Records.
Contents List
- Series I. Correspondence, 1774-1978., Extent: 13 boxes. (Box 1-13)
  There are two groups of correspondence. The first group covers the period 1774 to 1978 and is arranged chronologically. The earliest letters are written by James W. Foster (1807-1866) to his wife while he was serving in the Virginia General Assembly in Richmond. There are also letters written by John S. Knox, Sr. (1827-1906) in Alexandria to his wife. There are Civil War letters written by David Holmes Conrad (1800-1877) of Martinsburg, (West) Virginia to James W. Foster (concerning the deaths of his sons Holmes Addison Conrad (1837-1861) and Henry Tucker Conrad (1839-1861), while they were serving with the 2nd Virginia Infantry at Manassas. There are also letters from Dr. Arthur Moray Randolph (1815-1867) of Tallahassee, Florida regarding the death of his son Thomas Easton Randolph (1841-1862) of the 1st Florida Infantry. The other Civil War letters are written by Thomas Hunton Foster (1835-1864) to his father while he was a prisoner of war at Point Lookout, Maryland. There is a 1902 letter from Eppa Hunton (1822-1908) containing comments on his son's law practice and attendance at the Constitutional Convention in Richmond. There is a good deal of correspondence to and from Turner Foster and his brother E. Carter Foster (1895-1973) while they were attending Episcopal High School in Alexandria, and while Turner Foster was attending Bogue Institute in Indianapolis, and Hatfield Institute in Chicago. Finally, this group contains letters written while Turner Foster was employed in thrashing and harvesting jobs out West in Colorado, Kansas, Minnesota, New Mexico, and Oklahoma. There are also postcards written by him during this period in the Subject Files.
  The second group of correspondence covers the years 1930 to 1972 and is arranged by year (with some gaps), and thereunder alphabetically by surname or topic. This group concerns mainly to the operation of Glenville Farm. It contains correspondence, as well as accounts and receipts, pertaining to seed, fertilizer, feed, coal, gas, and oil, livestock and equipment purchases, sales, and repairs, warranty information, hiring of farm hands, stock purchases and dividends, vestry and financial information relating to Grace Church, insurance and taxes, and other matters. There is a good deal of correspondence from the Department of Agriculture, the Virginia Aberdeen-Angus Association, the Fauquier National Bank of Warrenton, and information on various speech classes and institutes. Finally, there are many letters between Foster and his siblings concerning the settlement of their mother's estate and the sale of Glenville.
  - 1774. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1835. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1837. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1841. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1842. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1856. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1859. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1860. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1861. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1862. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1863. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1864. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1865. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1866. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1869. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1875. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1876. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1877. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1880. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1882. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1890. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1891. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1896. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1897. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1898. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 1899. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 1900. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 1902. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 1904. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 1905. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 1906. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 1908. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 1909. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 1910. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - 1911. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - 1912. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 1913. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 1915. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 1916 (January-February). (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 1916 (March-December). (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 1917 (January-February). (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1917 (March-April). (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1917 (May-December). (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1918 (January-October). (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1918 (November-December). (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1919. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1920. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1921. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1922. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1925. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1927. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1928. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1929. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1930. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1931. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1932. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1933. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1934. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1935. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1938. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 1945. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 1954. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 1967. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 1969. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 1978. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - n.d.. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 1930-1932 (A-Z). (Box 3, Folder 1-15)
  - 1935-1938 (A-B). (Box 3, Folder 16-18)
  - 1935-1938 (C-Z). (Box 4, Folder 1-13)
  - 1938-1941 (A-G). (Box 4, Folder 14-19)
  - 1938-1941 (H-Z). (Box 5, Folder 1-9)
  - 1942-1945 (A-F). (Box 5, Folder 10-15)
  - 1942-1945 (G-Z). (Box 6, Folder 1-10)
  - 1945-1949 (A-J). (Box 6, Folder 11-17)
  - 1945-1949 (K-Z). (Box 7, Folder 1-8)
  - 1949-1953 (A-M). (Box 7, Folder 9-18)
  - 1949-1953 (N-Z). (Box 8, Folder 1-6)
  - 1953-1960 (A-Q). (Box 8, Folder 7-18)
  - 1953-1960 (R-Z). (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
  - 1957-1959 (A-Q). (Box 9, Folder 5-17)
  - 1957-1959 (R-Z). (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
  - 1960-1962 (A-Z). (Box 10, Folder 5-19)
  - 1962-1964 (A-Z). (Box 11, Folder 1-16)
  - 1969-1970 (A-B). (Box 11, Folder 17-18)
  - 1969-1970 (C-Z). (Box 12, Folder 1-13)
  - 1971-1972 (A-Z). (Box 13, Folder 1-15)
- Series II. Financial Records, 1859-1972., Extent: 18 boxes. (Box 14-29, 43-44)
  The majority of the financial records are bills and receipts that are arranged by year, and thereunder alphabetically by company name or type of product purchased. Included are records for livestock purchases and registrations, hardware and building materials, clothing and general merchandise, feed, seed, and fertilizer, vehicles and equipment repairs, insurance premiums, veterinary services, telephone and electric bills, periodical subscriptions and membership dues, and payments for work by farm hands. This series also contains numerous account books, check stub books, farm and personal account books, ledgers, day books, tax tickets and receipts, as well as personal accounts and receipts (1919-1923) of Mrs. James R. Foster. There are also financial statements and annual reports of various corporations in which Foster owned stock, including AT&T, Coca-Cola, Eastman Kodak, General Motors, General Electric, Procter and Gamble, RCA, Standard Oil, and U.S. Steel. They date from the mid-1920's to mid-1930's. Also included in this series are annual statements of Glenville Farm (1925-1952 and 1966), which detail receipts and disbursements, and yearly expenses, including livestock bought and sold, crops sold, fertilizer and seed purchases, gas and kerosene purchases, repairs and improvements, wages paid, money borrowed, equipment purchases, taxes, veterinary services, and other expenses relating to the maintenance of Glenville Farm.
  - Account Book, 1891-1927. (Box 43)
  - Account Books, 1918-1919. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Account Book, 1922-1924. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Account Book, 1924-1925. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Accounts and Receipts, 1880-1914. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Bills, 1951-1954 (A-V). (Box 14, Folder 5-21)
  - Bills, 1951-1954 (W-Z). (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Bills, 1954-1957 (A-Z). (Box 15, Folder 2-20)
  - Bills, 1957-1960 (A-Z). (Box 16, Folder 1-16)
  - Bills, 1961-1963 (B-Z). (Box 17, Folder 1-17)
  - Bills, 1967-1968 (A-Z). (Box 18, Folder 1-16)
  - Bills, 1969-1970 (A-G). (Box 18, Folder 17-22)
  - Bills, 1969-1970 (H-Z). (Box 19, Folder 1-9)
  - Bills, 1971-1972 (A-S). (Box 19, Folder 10-23)
  - Bills, 1971-1972 (T-Z). (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
  - Check Stub Books, 1886-1965. (Box 44)
  - Day Book, 28 September 1859 - December 1863. (Box 43)
  - Diary and Ledger, 1880-1918. (Box 43)
  - Farm Account Book, 1921-1923. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Farm and Personal Account Book, 1921-1923. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Index to Farm and Personal Account Book. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Farm Diary and Account Book, 1916-1921. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Farm Income and Expense Records, 1953-1954. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Fauquier National Bank - Statements of Condition, 1945-1965. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Financial Condition of T. Turner Foster, 1922-1925. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Financial Statements (A-F). (Box 20, Folder 11-13)
  - Financial Statements (G-S). (Box 21, Folder 1-10)
  - Ledger, 1900-1907. (Box 43)
  - Receipts, 1918-1919. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Receipts, 1920-1930 (A-C). (Box 21, Folder 12-14)
  - Receipts, 1920-1930 (C-Z). (Box 22, Folder 1-17)
  - Receipts, 1930-1936 (A-Z). (Box 23, Folder 1-19)
  - Receipts, 1945-1949 (A-S). (Box 24, Folder 1-17)
  - Receipts, 1945-1949 (T-Z). (Box 25, Folder 1-3)
  - Receipts, 1949-1951 (A-Z). (Box 25, Folder 4-21)
  - Receipts - Mrs. James R. Foster, 1919-1923. (Box 26, Folder 1-6)
  - Statements of Glenville Farm, 1925-1927. (Box 26, Folder 7-9)
  - Statements of Glenville Farm, 1928-1939. (Box 27, Folder 1-13)
  - Statements of Glenville Farm, 1940-1949. (Box 28, Folder 1-10)
  - Statements of Glenville Farm, 1950, 1952, 1966. (Box 29, Folder 1-3)
  - Tax Tickets and Receipts, 1894-1938. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Taxes Paid, 1892-1919. (Box 29, Folder 5)
- Series III. Subject Files, 1740-1978., Extent: 11 boxes. (Box 30-36, 39, 45-47)
  The subject files include Bible records, books, certificates, clippings, deeds, and diaries, including reminiscences, written by Foster in 1968, of his time employed as a harvest hand out West in 1919. The subject files also contain Episcopal High School memorabilia, estate papers, a framed pencil drawing of Lucelia Hunton Foster (1811-1888), historical notes on the Civil War and Glenville, genealogical notes on the Carter, Foster, and Turner families, guardians' accounts, insurance papers, invitations, memorandum books, photographs and photograph albums, obituaries, copies of "The Parish Leaflet" for Piedmont and Whittle Parishes, plats and surveys, postcards, scrapbooks, and other items.
  - Abstract of Title. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Adams vs. Cochran. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Address Book. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Agreements. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Alderman Library - UVA. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Alexandria Gazette, 20 December 1865. (Box 47)
  - Anderson, Wesley. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Appointment - Officers' Reserve Corps, 1917. (Box 47)
  - Armenian Relief Fund. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Baby Book - Elizabeth Horner Robins. (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Gov. James Barbour Letter. (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - "Beautiful and Historic Piedmont Virginia" - Issued by the Warrenton and Fairfax Turnpike Company. (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Bible Records. (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Billfold - Myers and Houseman (Baltimore). (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Blotters. (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Bogue Institute for Stammerers. (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Boy Scouts. (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Broadsides and Circulars. (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Brooks, Jack H.. (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Bryn Mawr School Banquets, 1922-1923. (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - "The Carter Tree" - Compiled by Robert Randolph Carter of Shirley, 1951. (Box 45)
  - Certificate - Farmers' National Congress Delegate, 1910. (Box 47)
  - Certificates. (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Chatham Episcopal Institute - "The Chathamite," May 1909. (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Civil War History. (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Clippings. (Box 30, Folder 22-24)
  - Code Book. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - "College Topics" - University of Virginia, 21 September 1910. (Box 47)
  - Colonial Dames of America. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Confederate Stamp. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Copper Plate. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Deeds, 1819-1905. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Deeds, 1906-1974. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Diary, 1919. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Diary, 1920-1921. (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Diary, 1921. (Box 31, Folder 9-10)
  - Diary, 1922-1927. (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Diary, n.d.. (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - "Diary of a Roving Harvest Hand in 1919" by T. Turner Foster, 1968. (Box 31, Folder 13-14)
  - "Diddie, Dumps, and Tot or Plantation Child-Life" by Louise-Clarke Pyrnelle, 1882. (Box 45)
  - Document Box. (Box 42)
  - "Elements of Geometry and Trigonometry From the Works of A.M. Legrende" by Charles Davies, 1866. (Box 45)
  - Episcopal High School. (Box 31, Folder 15-16)
  - Estate of James R. Foster. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Estate of Mary B. Hunton Foster. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Estate of Mary Carter Foster. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Estate of Mary E. Foster. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Estate of Thomas R. Foster. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Estate of T. Turner Foster. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Estate of James Samuel Hall. (Box 32, Folder 7-10)
  - Estate of Jane C. Hunton. (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Estate of Jane Carter Foster Palmer (Funeral Program). (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - "Faber's Hymns" by Frederick W. Faber, D.D., 1875. (Box 45)
  - "Faithfully Yours, Charles Green" by Martha L. Summerell. (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Family Bibles. (Box 45-46)
  - Fauquier County Map and Historical Notes, 1914. (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Fauquier County - Historical Notes. (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Fauquier Historical Society. (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Fire - The Plains, 21 February 1967. (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Foster, James William. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Foster, Lucelia Hunton - Pencil Drawing on Canvas. (Box 47)
  - Foster Memorial Window - Grace Church. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Genealogical Notes. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Genealogical Notes - Carter/Turner. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Genealogical Notes - Foster. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Genessee Valley Breeders Association. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Glenville - History. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Glenville - Sales Brochure. (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Grace Church. (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Greeting Cards. (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Guardian's Accounts - Jane Turner Foster. (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Guardian's Accounts - Margaret M. Foster. (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Guardian's Accounts - Edward S. Turner. (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Guardian's Accounts - Margaret F. Turner. (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Guardian's Accounts - Mary B. Turner. (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Guardian's Accounts - Margaret F., Edward S., and Mary B. Turner. (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Handwriting Exercise Book. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Hunton, Laura. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Immigration Visa Application. (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Insurance. (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Invitations. (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - B. F. Keith's Theatre, Washington, DC, 1914. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Land Grants. (Box 47)
  - Robert E. Lee Photograph - Documentation. (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - "A List of 'Lost' Alumni of the University of Virginia," 1912. (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Livestock Contracts, 1892-1894. (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Livestock Purchases, 1913-1917. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - "Luke the Angus Steer" - Story by E. Carter Foster. (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Mailing List. (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Manassas Gap Railroad Company. (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Marriage Certificate - Foster/Robins, 1929. (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Memorandum Book, 1881-1919. (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Memorandum Book, 1914. (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Memorandum Book, 1919-1920. (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Memorandum Book, 1920. (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Memorandum Book, 1920-1922. (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Memorandum Book, 1921-1923. (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Memorandum Book, 1922. (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Memorandum Book, 1922-1923. (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - Memorandum Book, 1923. (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - "Memorial of the Unveiling of Lee's Statue," 29 May 1890. (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Mosher Book List, 1913. (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Mount Mineral Farm. (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - "The New Latin Tutor" by Frederic P. Leverett, 1845. (Box 45)
  - "The New Peace Palace" by James W. Foster. (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Obituaries. (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - "Old Farmer's Almanac," 1863. (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - "The Parish Leaflet" - Piedmont and Whittle Parishes, 1915-1918. (Box 35, Folder 7-10)
  - Passports. (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Patent - Improvement in Manufacturing Malt Liquors, 1879. (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Perpetual Calendar. (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Peyton, Robert E., Jr.. (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Photograph Albums. (Box 40)
  - Photographs. (Box 41)
  - Plat - Meadowville, 1927. (Box 47)
  - Plats and Surveys. (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Poetry 1915. (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Postcards. (Box 39)
  - Power of Attorney, 1959. (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - "Pure Drinking Water for Country Homes," 1930. (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Religious Pamphlets and Publications. (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Report Cards. (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - Ribbons 1915. (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - School Compositions. (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - School Notes. (Box 35, Folder 23)
  - Scrapbook - Elizabeth W. Knox. (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook - Elizabeth Robins (World War I). (Box 36, Folder 2-3)
  - "Sesame and Lilies and the King of the Golden River" by John Ruskin, 1921. (Box 45)
  - Slaughter, Philip - Relief. (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - The Southern Churchman, 7 June 1866. (Box 47)
  - Stamp Act Protest, 1765 (copy). (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Stock Certificate - Fauquier County Agricultural Society. (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Switzerland Trip. (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Thomas R. Foster and Company. (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Thomas Turner Association. (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - "Titanic" Picture Section - The New York Times, 28 April 1912. (Box 47)
  - Tractor Manuals. (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Turner Reunion. (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - University of Virginia Programs, 1913. (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Virginia Folk-Lore Society, 1913. (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Warrenton Fire, 1909. (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Warrenton Hunt Club Race Program, 1914. (Box 47)
  - White House Invitation, 1940. (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Whitewood. (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Whitewood - Cemetery Work. (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Whitewood - Sale. (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Will of Josephine Knox Robins. (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - World Map. (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - World War Memorial Hall and Miles Stadium Dedication, 23 October 1926. (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - "The Years of Anguish, Fauquier County, Virginia, 1861-1865" by the Fauquier County Civil War Centennial Committee, 1965. (Box 45)
- Series IV. Scott District Road Board Records, 1923-1927., Extent: 1 box. (Box 37)
  Turner Foster served as a member of the Scott District Road Board. The records cover the period from 1923 to 1927, and include budgets, correspondence (a good deal of it is with the Board's chairman Thomas B. Glascock), minutes, petitions, road workers' accounts, pay rolls, and expense accounts, relating to condition, maintenance, improvements, and construction of roads in Fauquier County.
  - A. (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - B. (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Budgets. (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Cox, Eppa S.. (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - D. (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - E-F. (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - G. (Box 37, Folder 7-8)
  - H-I-J. (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - K-L. (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - M. (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - N-O. (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - P-Q. (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Pay Rolls and Expense Accounts. (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - R. (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - S. (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Scott District Road System. (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - T-U-V. (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Turner, R. R.. (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - W-X-Y-Z. (Box 37, Folder 21)
- Series V. Millard Institute of Normal Speech Records, 1926., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 38-39)
  The Millard Institute of Normal Speech records detail Foster's establishment and operation of a branch of the Institute in the basement of the Fauquier County courthouse. Foster had attended the Institute, located in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, and was impressed by its teaching methods and the treatment he received. The files contain class exercise notebooks, contracts, correspondence, financial records, a card file of prospective students, and a copy of "The Millard Instructor - A Key to Perfect Speech" by Lee Wells Millard.
  - Card File of Prospective Students. (Box 39)
  - Class Exercise Notebooks. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Contracts. (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence. (Box 38, Folder 3-4)
  - Financial Records. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - "The Millard Instructor". (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Students. (Box 38, Folder 7)